HOW TO USE THE TILE SYSTEM

The tile system is primarily created to allow a user to interface with the tilemap in easy to modify and extend ways. It allows you to change the tile’s art, store tile info, give a tile procedural instructions, and of course access and change the data within them.


Getting started:
	
      The singleton: 
      The singleton “TileManager.TM” allows a user to access all tile maps and hexagonal interfacing. It’s a singleton so it can be accessed from anywhere without needing to pass a reference. To use anything in this class, you can access it via typing TileManager.TM.
      
      Methods:
      
      
      ScreenToHex(Vector3Int screenPos )
      ViewPortToHex(Vector3 viewPos)
      WorldToHex(Vector3 worldPos)
      	
These three Methods allow a programmer to convert from game coords to an actual Hex coordinate.

      public Hex getMouseHex()
      
      A simplified method provided for just clicking
      which returns the Hex that the mouse is hovering over;

	public bool isValidHex(Hex hex)
	
		You can also input a hex coord to see if it is in or outside the play area

	public Hex[] getNeighbors(Hex hex)
		
		returns the hex neighbors

	public Hex[] getValidNeighbors(Hex hex)
		
		returns the valid hex neighbors



Tile Handlers
	Calling TileManager.TM[“map”] will get you the main tile handler currently in the scene. If you duplicate the tileMap


	

Tiles:
	Tiles are the code based part of the tile system, I’ve created a flexible general purpose tile for coders to use. You can also use these tiles to store data on a per tile basis. There are 4 overridable methods in each tile. 

To create a new tile, just inherit the class TileTemp

	void LoadArt()
		use to get all needed art assets from the art repository
		by default loads a blank white tile
	
	void Start()
		use for initializing the tile, 
		by default does nothing

	void Behavior()
		use for update logic every frame
		by default does nothing

	void End()
		put code here that will run when the tile is removed from the board
		by default does nothing

the tile also has a field called “currentArt” which can be assigned a Tile art to change what gets drawn 

TileArt:
	In the unity file explorer, right click and go to the “create” tab. 
	
	There is an object in the scene called “create new tileArt”
	
	If you click it you’ll see a new asset that accepts a sprite and a name, place a sprite in it and name it with a unique name
	
	In the unity scene, there is an object called the art repository, with a list of tile art assets, you can place it here,	

	Now, when creating a tile, you can get this piece of art by just typing:
      
       TileArtRepository.Art[(INSERT TILEART NAME YOU ASSIGNED)]




	

	


	

